Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree:



Senior Systems Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Automation Consultant



Current Designation: Senior Systems Engineer

Current Company: Infosys Limited

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Pref. Location: Gurgaon, Hyderabad, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Python, Elastic Search, Java, SAP PI

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Having total 4.2 years of work experience .

Experience in Design, Development and Implementation of various Python bots and usecases .

Experienced in Machine learning bots like sentiment analysis.

Basic knowledge in Java, Elastic search, Hadoop and Spark, Machine Learning.

 $Good\ Handson\ Experience\ in\ Python\ OOPS\ concepts,\ Python\ rest\ API\ concepts,\ Python\ collections\ ,\ exception\ handling\ ,$ 

Python with Elastic Search, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL.

Excellent communication, Analytical, Problem solving and Interpersonal skills.

Very good team player, ability to work in a team as well as independently and quick at mastering new concepts and applications,

flexible and adaptable to any working conditions.

## **Work Experience**

Infosys Limited as Senior Systems Engineer

Aug 2016 to Till Date

LIVE PROJECTS: 1

Project Title: BotFactory Development and Deployment

Client: Detusche Bank

Duration: From September 2018 to Present

Description: BotFactory is a product of Infosys Limited which is used for developing various reusable Microbots,workerbots and implementing various client related Usecases. Usecases can be implemented in various technologies like Java, Python, .Net , RPA , Machine learning ,etc . Camunda BPMN is used for creating automation workflow in BotFactory environment for various usecases . Automation workflows are tested and finally deployed in client environment.

Responsibilities:

Analyze the requirement with the clients on an ongoing basis.

Followed agile methodology.

Involved in design and development for various bots .

Participated in client interaction meetings.

Performed stiching of various technology bots to create a workflow Tested bots and workflows on Camunda BPMN platform.

#### **Environment:**

IDE: Eclipse, VisualStudioCode, Jupyter Notebook

Technologies: Python, Java Databases: PostGreSQL Tools: Camunda BPMN, JIRA

LIVE PROJECTS: 2

Project Title: Unilever SAP PI Landscape Maintenance

Client: Unilever

Duration: From December 2016 to August 2018

Description: SAP PI is a middleware integration system used to facilitate the exchange of information among a company's

internal

software and systems and those of external parties .

#### Responsibilities:

Supporting end to end root cause analysis for a business or technical issue utilizing SAP workbench tools.

Troubleshooting of errors in Adapter Engine, various critical communication channels and interfaces.

Coordinating with the ABAP team, Basis team, Development team, Country users and onsite team for development and

technical support activities during go-live and post go-live

Worked on Incident Analysis and resolution activities.

Handling ITM Outage Management and Monthly Releases.

Explaining technical issues to clients and define solutions to the issue.

Coordinated and mediated the activities between the offshore team members and clients at onsite.

#### **Environment:**

IDE: Eclipse

Technologies: SAP PI 7.3 Databases: Oracle Database

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Hindustan Institute of Technology and Science, Chennai in 2016

PG: in 0

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Python for Data Science and Al Machine learning with Python

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Python	
JAVA	
Oracle Database	
git, Jira	
Visual Studio Code	
Jupyter Notebook	
Eclipse	
WINDOWS	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

## **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

**Employment Status: Full time**